# Roman Budnikov

Golang Developer work@romanyx.ru https://romanyx.ru

### Summary

Software Engineer with more than 6 years of experience in web development, former Ruby on Rails full stack developer. SOLID enthusiast with the experience in unit and integration testing. Learner and a team player dedicated to solving problems. Willing to take ownership of core components.

## Skill Highlights

- Fluent in Go
- vim
- gRPC, REST API
- NATS, RabbitMQ
- Postgres, MySQL
- Docker, Kubernetes
- Jaeger, Prometheus

- SOLID
- Clean Architecture
- Testing
- Microservices
- OpenCensus

# Experience

Integral LLC remote

Back-end Golang Developer

2018-11 / present

- Building microservices architecture on top of NATS with «gogoproto» for banking purposes.
- Integration with online banking API for user identification and accounting.
- Writing idiomatic and testable Go code.
- Logging, metrics and tracing with OpenCensus, Jaeger, and Prometheus.
- Performance profiling.
- Taking part in reviewing team pull requests.
- Writing reliable unit and integration tests with Docker.
- Applying Clean Architecture and Domain Driven Design.

**Bitstinct** remote

Back-end Golang Developer

2017-06 / 2019-02

- Writing clients for crypto-currency exchange markets API.
- Calculating exchange rates based on incoming order books from crypto-currency exchanges.
- Building REST API for front-end needs on top of Swagger using «go-swagger».

Writing reliable unit and integration tests with Docker.

ARS-VISION remote

Full Stack Ruby on Rails Developer

2016-07 / 2017-06

- Developed various projects with Ruby on Rails.
- Developed front-end with React.js.
- Wrote reliable unit and integration tests.

**Fireimp** remote

Founder, CTO 2015 / 2016

- Developed the API for front-end using Ruby on Rails.
- Developed front-end using React.js.
- Developed online WYSIWYG editor for writers using Websockets and Go.
- Developed parsers for most popular gaming websites to monitor the latest news.
- Developed Slack bot for informing redaction about the news.
- Deployed the code on production using Capistrano.
- Set up the production environment.
- Organized the working process of the redaction.

**Relocom** remote

Full Stack ROR Developer / Lead ROR Developer

2013-02 / 2016-07

- Developed REST API on top of Rails for the web app.
- Developed front-end with the usage of Ember.js
- Deployed the code on production using Capistrano.
- Troubleshot production environment problems.
- Built search API with the ElasticSearch.

**Crimeainfocom** Simferopol, Ukraine

Networking engineer 2011-02 / 2013-02

- Monitored and solved networking problems.
- Built the monitoring system to monitor clients bandwidth.
- Administrated the billing program and a server.
- Developed CRM with Ruby on Rails.

#### Education

## Manager, specialist

Tavrida National University — Simferopol, Ukraine 2007-2012